Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Athletic Department, 1969-present UPG.RG.21
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Athletic Department
1969-present
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.21
3 boxes
Administrative Records of the Athletic Department of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 1969-present.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Custodial History
Transferred from the UPG Athletic Department to the UPG Archives.
See Also
Scrapbooks housed in Archives Utility [Cabinet 1]
UPG.RG.02.1 Pres. Smith, Dr. Albert B. Ser.: Subject Files -- Basketball 1970-1974
For Print of Cheerleader Team (1969/70) see: UPG Archives UPG.RG.60 Visual Images. See: Prints – Cheerleaders
Men's Basketball Alumni Club (MBAC) [Pitt-Greensburg Men's Basketball Alumni Club (MBAC) See: UPG.RG.39.2 Pitt-Greensburg Alumni Association Ser.: Subject Files. Men's Basketball Alumni Club.
Ice Hockey See: UPG.RG.38 Ser.: Student Organizations. Ice Hockey Club.
UPG Bobcat Golf Outing [Bobcat Golf Outing] Later Pitt-Greensburg Golf Outing in UPG.RG.52 Subject Files--Pitt-Greensburg Golf Outing
Scope and Content Notes
Director of Athletics and Recreation, Athletic Committee, Bobcat Team (The Official Booster Club of UPG Athletics), Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act (EADA), Publications, Sports Awards Ceremony & Reception [Sports Banquet];[Athletic Award Ceremony];[Scholar-Athlete Awards Ceremony], Sports Schedule, Sports, UPG Bobcat Golf Outing [Bobcat Golf Outing]; Pitt-Greensburg Golf Outing
Universities and colleges –- Pennsylvania –- Greensburg –- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- Director of Athletics and Recreation, 1994-2018; I.
  - General File, 1994-2018; 1.
    Scope and Content Notes
    Contains: memo dtd 8/2/94 from Rick Fogle to the Enrollment Management Committee, Subject: UPG Athletics, Basketball and Baseball; Minutes 8/16/94, Enrollment Management Committee, "Planned Improvements for the '94-'95 Intramural Program"; Employment Management Initiatives [undtd]"; "Resolution to Implement a Student Athletic Fee at the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg" passed by the University of Pittsburgh Board of Trustees at its annual meeting of June 22, 1995
    Fall Term [2141 Term] Athletes vs. General Population GPA's [Sept. 2014]
    9/8/05 [Announcement] Assistant Women's Basketball Coach, Sports Information Director, Other Coaching Assignment, Full-Time Position, Description of Application Procedures and Job Duties.
    [2014] Fall Term [2141 Term] Athletes vs. General Population GPA's [Sept. 2014]
    2018 [News Clippings GTR 8/20/2018] "Pitt-Greensburg Hires Yetter [Jeromy] as AD".
    2018 [News Clipping: The Insider] "Jeromy Yetter Returns as New Athletics Director".
    2018 [News Release 8/20/2018] "Jeromy Yetter named Athletic Director at Pitt-Greensburg".
    - General File, 1994-2018 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
- Athletic Committee, 1994-1995; II.
  Contains: Agenda for meeting, Oct. 5, 1994 and includes mission statement of the committee; Athletic Program, Target Fall 1995; UPG Athletics Fundraising Possibilities; memo from Dr. Mark McColloch dtd 10/4/94 (DMD could not attend the 10/5/94 meeting but wished to raise issues of concerns to him); agenda for 3/1/95 meeting; "Pitt-Greensburg 5 Year Plan, Intercollegiate Athletics" with a 5 year outline; "Budget Narrative'; "Collegiate Fall 1995 Athletic Program, Athletic Update 6/7/95".
  - Athletic Committee, 1994-1995 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
- Bobcat Team (The Official Booster Club of UPG Athletics), III.
  - Bobcat Team (The Official Booster Club of UPG Athletics) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
- Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act (EADA), 1994-2000; IV.
  The Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act of 1994, Section 360B of Public Law 103-382 requires that any institution of higher education that participates in any federal student financial aid program and has intercollegiate athletic programs must provide information concerning their intercollegiate athletic programs under the act.
  Archives has reports: 9-95/4-96, 9-96/4-97, 9/97-6/98, 1998/1999, 1999/2000
  - Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act (EADA), 1994-2000 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
- Publications, 1990-present; V.
  - Brochures, Posters [Spirit Cards], 1996-2010; 1.
    The University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg. NCAA By 2000. Campaign for Intercollegiate Athletics. 1996-2000. [Brochures]
    University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg "Let's Go Bobcats" "On the Prowl" [Poster] [2007]
    University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg "Ready to Pounce" 2007-2008 Men's & Women's Basketball [Poster [Spirit Card]] [2008]
    Poster. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg [Basketball Schedule 2009-2010] [Sponsor: Toyota Scion of Greensburg Home of the Lifetime Warranty]
    See Also
    Filed UPG.qRG.52 Subject Files--Posters. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg [Basketball Schedule...] [Housed in Map Case]
    - Brochures, Posters [Spirit Cards], 1996-2010 (Map-case 1, Drawer 9, Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Bobcats, 1998-1999; 2.
    [Includes: 1998 Men's Soccer Roster; 1998 Men's Soccer Results; 1998 Women's Volleyball Roster; 1998 Women's Volleyball Results; 1998-99 Cheerleaders; 1998-99 Dance Team; 1998 Women's Tennis Roster; 1998 Women's Fall Tennis 1998 Schedule; UPG Men's Basketball 1997-98; UPG Women's Basketball 1997-98; 1998-99 Women's Basketball Roster; 1998-99 Women's Basketball Schedule; 1998-99 Men's Golf Roster; 1999 Women's Softball Roster; 1998-99 Men's Baseball Roster; Spring 1999 Men's Baseball Schedule.]
    - Bobcats, 1998-1999 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Bobcat Basketball (1999-2000), 3.
    [1999-2000 Women's Basketball Roster; 1999-2000 Women's Basketball Schedule; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Women's Basketball, 1998-1999 Final Statistics; Women's Basketball All-Time Records; 1999-2000 Men's Basketball Roster; 1999-2000 Men's Basketball Schedule; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Men's Basketball 1998-1999 Final Statistics; Men's Basketball All-Time Records; 1999-2000 Cheerleaders; 1999-2000 Dance Team; Athletic's [sic] Department--names of Administrators, Coaches, Trainer, Senior Women's Administrator, Faculty Athletic's [sic] Representative; Compliance Officer; Founder of the 6th Man]
    - Bobcat Basketball (1999-2000) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Bobcat Basketball (2000-2001), 4.
    [Contents: Athletics Dept. -- names of Administrators, Coaches, Faculty Athletic's Representative, Compliance Officer; Founder of the 6th Man; 2000-2001 Women's Basketball Roster; 2000-2001 Women's Basketball Schedule; Women's Basketball All-Time Records; 2000-2001 Men's Basketball Roster; 2000-2001 Men's Basketball Schedule; Men's Basketball All-Time Records; 2000-2001 Cheerleaders; 2000-2001 Dance Team]
    - Bobcat Basketball (2000-2001) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Bobcat Basketball (2003-2004), 5.
    [Contents: Athletics Dept.--names of Administrators, Coaches, Faculty Athletics Representative, Compliance Officer; Women's Basketball Schedule, 2003-2004; Women's Basketball Roster, 2003-2004; Women's Basketball Coaches; Women's Basketball 2002-2003 Season in Review; Women's Basketball All-Time Records; Pitt-Greensburg Women's Basketball All-Time Roster; Pitt-Greensburg Men's Basketball; Men's Basketball Schedule, 2003-2004; Men's Basketball Roster, 2003-2004; Men's Basketball Coaches; Men's Basketball 2002-2003 Season in Review; Men's Basketball All-Time Records; Pitt-Greensburg Men's Basketball All-Time Roster; Cheerleaders; Dance Team; Home Opponents Information.]
    - Bobcat Basketball (2003-2004) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Intramural Sports Handbook [UPG Intramurals], 1990-1991; 6.
    - Intramural Sports Handbook [UPG Intramurals], 1990-1991 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Sports Information Release, 1996-2006; 7.
    Sports Update [Bobcat Weekly Updates]. December 9, 1996- 1996 December 9, 16 1997 January 13, 20, 27 February 3, 10, 24 March 17/24 March 31/Apr. 8 April 10-16, 17 (End of Spring Term) November 17-23 November 25-December 1 December 2-9 December 10-17 1997/98 December 16-January 8 1998 January 5-12 January 12-19 January 20-26 January 27-February 2 February 3-10 February 10-17 February 17-24 February 24-March 3 March 10-17 April 30 September 29 October 21 November 2, 12, 24 December 8, 14, 22 1999 January 12, 21, 26 February 2, 9, 16, 24 March 3, 23, 31 Apr. 7, 14 Oct. 11, 18, [Oct. 18 last issue for 1999] 2000 January 17, Feb. 6, 13, 27 2000: Sept. 22, Oct. 9, 16 2000/01 Sept. 19, 27, Oct. 2, 9, 16, 23, 31, Nov. 6, 20, 27, Dec. 4, 11, Jan. 15, 22, 29, Feb. 5, 12, 19, 26, Mar. 12, 19, 26, April 2, 9, 16, 23, May 5, 18 2001/02 Sept. 3, 10, 17, 24, Oct. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29, Nov. 5, 19, 26, Dec. 3, 10, Jan. 7, 14, 21, 28, Feb. 4, 11, 18, 25, Mar. 18, 25, Apr. 1, 8, 15, 22 2002/03 Sept. 7-July 7 2003/04 Aug. 14, 2003-Dec. 30, 2004 2005, Jan 3-Jan. 4, 2006
    - Sports Information Release, 1996-2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 4)
  - Pitt-Greensburg Athletics Web Site: Headlines For Articles Posted On The Pitt-Greensburg Web Site, April 2009-April 2011; 8.
    [Archives holds only headlines and some abstracts of articles which appeared on the web site. Entries arranged in reverse chronological order.]
    - Pitt-Greensburg Athletics Web Site: Headlines For Articles Posted On The Pitt-Greensburg Web Site, April 2009-April 2011 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Sports Articles In The UPG Insider, 2/28/2006-4/12/2009; 9.
    Annotated brief listing of [UPG] Insider articles, principally, on UPG sports programs but with some limited coverage of Pitt (Oakland Campus) athletic programs, i.e., football and basketball. List is in reverse chronological order. The [UPG] Insider must be consulted for full texts of the articles. Period of coverage: 2/28/06-4/12/09.
    - Sports Articles In The UPG Insider, 2/28/2006-4/12/2009 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Sports Update, 12/9/1996-1/4/2006; 10.
    - Sports Update, 12/9/1996-1/4/2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5, Box 4)
- Sports Awards Ceremony & Reception [Sports Banquet]; [Athletic Award Ceremony]; [Scholar-Athlete Awards Ceremony], 2000-2016; VI.
  Spring 2000 (April 9, 2000) Fall 2000 (November 10, 2000) Spring 2001 (April 8, 2001) Fall 2001 (November 18, 2001) Spring 2002 (April 14, 2002) Fall 2002 (December 6, 2002) Spring 2003 (April 13, 2003) Fall 2003 (December 7, 2003) Spring 2004 (May 8, 2004) Fall 2004 (Dec. 10, 2004) Spring 2005 (April 3, 2005) Spring 2005 (May 22, 2005) 2006, April 2. Winter Sports Awards. 2006, May 12. Spring Sports Awards. 2007, April 16. Department of Athletics First Annual All-Sports Award Banquet. [Program gives: 2006-2007 AMCC All-American Academic Team; AMCC All-Conference Performers; Department of Athletics Sport Team Achievements, 1997-2005; Department of Athletics Chronological History 1995-2004; Department of Athletics Facilities 1989-2005.] 2008, April 15. Pitt-Greensburg Dept. of Athletics 2nd Annual All-Sports Award Banquet. [Program gives: AMCC All-American Academic Team, 2007-2008; AMCC All-Conference Performers; 2007-2008 Allegheny Mountain Collegiate Conference All-Conference Sportsmanship Team; UPG Dept. of Athletics Sport Team Achievements, 1997-2008.] May 30, 2009. 2009 Athletics Award Ceremony. [Program gives: Inspirational Athlete of the Year Award [Award winner not identified in program]; All-Conference Recognition [Names of athletes recognized are given]; Chi Alpha Sigma Inductees [names of inductees not given]; Male and Female Scholar Athlete Award Winners [names of winners not included in this program]; Individual Statistic Recognition [Nicole Reiser, 1000 points; Kelsey Wilcox, 1000 points; Dan Waajid, 1000 points]; Male and Female Athletes of the Year [Names not included in the program]. 2013, Feb. 21 [From Intercom 2/25-3/3/13: 78 athletes [honored] for their outstanding academic achievement]. 2014, Feb. 27. [Extract from Blue & Gold #105 Spring 2014, "Scholar-Athletes Recognized". 75 student-athletes recognized for outstanding academic achievement, Fall 2013 semester.] 2015, Feb. 19. [Extract from Blue & Gold #108 Winter/Spring 2015. "Scholar-Athletes [88] Recognized for Achievements" 2016, [Spring] [Extract from Blue & Gold #111, Spring 2016, Fall [2015] Athletic Season Successful. [Awards, honors]].
  For photos See: UPG.RG.60 Visual Images--Print--Sport Awards Banquet; Sports Awards Reception/Ceremony
  - Sports Awards Ceremony & Reception [Sports Banquet]; [Athletic Award Ceremony]; [Scholar-Athlete Awards Ceremony], 2000-2016 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
- Sports Schedule, 1996-2006; VII.
  1996/97 Fall & Winter
  1997, Fall
  1999, (NCAA Division III Fall Sports Program)
  2000, Fall/Winter (Men's Soccer, Men's Golf, Women's Soccer, Women's Tennis, Women's Volleyball, Fall Baseball, Women's Basketball, Men's Basketball)
  2000, Nov. 1 Men's Basketball vs. Arvika, Sweden
  2000, Nov. 1 Women's Basketball vs. Arvika, Sweden
  2000, Nov. 21 Women's Basketball vs. Carlow
  2001 Fall/Winter
  2006 Spring
  - Sports Schedule, 1996-2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
- Sports, 1969-present; VIII.
  - General, 1.
    - General (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Baseball (Men's), 2.
    - Baseball (Men's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5)
  - Basketball (Men's), 1969-1973, 2020; 3.
    UPG.RG.02.1 Pres. Smith, Dr. Albert B. Ser.: Subject Files -- Basketball 1970-1974
    For Print of Cheerleader Team (1969/70) see: UPG Archives UPG.RG.60 Visual Images. See: Prints – Cheerleaders
    Men's Basketball Alumni Club (MBAC) [Pitt-Greensburg Men's Basketball Alumni Club (MBAC) See: UPG.RG.39.2 Pitt-Greensburg Alumni Association Ser.: Subject Files. Men's Basketball Alumni Club.
    Basketball Strategy Plan Sheets. [undtd]
    First varsity athletic team (Men's Basketball) fielded in 1969/70. First team basketball roster: Harry Bowser, [Fred Charles],Dave Chesser, Bernie Cobetto, Dan Cottrell, Steve Frick, Rich Hardway, John Jamison, Tom Jollie, Tom Kristan, Mike Noppe, [Alan Person], [Paul Sailley], Al Skrabski. Coach, John Hunter. Asst. Coach, August "Gus" Corso First game played away at Pitt-Titusville, Nov. 15, 1969. Pitt-Greensburg 87, Pitt-Titusville 54. First home game with Penn State-New Kensington, Dec. 4, 1969. Pitt-Greensburg 92, Penn State-New Kensington 89. Home games played at Greensburg Salem High School gymnasium. Record first season: 4 wins, 8 losses.
    UPG Archives holds the following scrapbooks: Scrapbook, 1969/70. [Note: Housed in Utility [Cabinet 1]] Contains: news clippings, pictures, teams schedules, letters, statistics for the season. It also has a news story with newsprint picture of the first Cheerleader Team (1969/70) which included: Linda Adams, Karen Battistoni, Joan Boby, Donna DiMaria, Diane Kosic.)
    1969/1970 [File folder containing photocopied newspaper articles of the 1969/1970 UPG Basketball season. [Given to the Archives by Alan Hudock in 2016]].
    1970/71-1971/72 [File Folder containing photocopies of newspaper articles brought together and presented to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Men's Basketball Alumni Club by Mr. Alan Hudock. Includes: Final Statistics 1970/71; TD which identifies the Team Roster for 1970/71 and gives the names of the Coaches, Managers, Trainers, Score Keepers, Time Keeper, Statisticians, Team Physician, Cheerleaders, Advisors, Student Government Assoc. members. [Given to the Archives by Alan Hudock in 2016.]]
    Scrapbook, 1970/71-1971/1972 1 item [Note: Housed in Utility [Cabinet 1]] Contents: Primarily newspaper clippings with several other items of particular interest: 2 13" x 20" posters, "University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Basketball Schedules, 1970-71, 1971-72 (annotated with wins and losses; 1 form, "Final Statistics 1970-1971" which gives: name of player; games played; field goal attempts, field goal attempts made, turnovers committed, fouls attempted, fouls made with %, total points, game average, rebounds made, game average, fouls committed; 2 team group photos. [Given to the Archives by Alan Hudock in 2017.]
    Scrapbook, 1972/73. [Note: Housed in Utility [Cabinet 1]] Contains: news clippings, pictures, team schedule, 1972/73 team members included: Vince Dalicandro, Jeff Dodds, Robert Domenick, Michael Dunn, Jerry Fedele, Paul Floder, Michael Kasunic, Richard Kruzynzki, Mark Kudlik, Richard McFeeley, John Messner, Jim Murphy, Tony Quatrini, David Shaler, Jeff Systir. Coach, John Hunter. (Richard Kruzynski received the first annual Golden Panther Scholar-Athlete Award.)
    Booklets 1970-1973 A. University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Dept. of Athletics. 1970/71-1971/72 Contains inter alia: Coach Profiles, Individual Team Member Profiles, All time Pitt-Greensburg Record (Leading Scorers, Individual Marks), Team Record (Most Points, Field Goals, Season Record, Basketball Roster, Season's Final Statistics). B. Programs. 1970-1972/73. 1970, Nov. 10, Penn State, Beaver; 1971, Jan. 4, New Castle Business College; Jan. 28, Community College of Allegheny Co., Boyce Campus; Feb. 15, St. Vincent J.V.'s; Dec. 2, New Castle Business College; [1971, Dec. 11 (?)] St. Vincent J.V.'s; 1972, Jan. 20, Allegheny County Community College, South Campus; Feb. 21, Penn State, New Kensington; 1973, Jan. 29, St. Vincent J.V.'s.
    Memorabilia
    Mementos from the time that Carlyle Carter was a member of the 1971/72 basketball team and earned his team's MVP Player Award for his performance in the 3rd Annual University of Pittsburgh Regional Campus Basketball Tournament [Pitt-Greensburg, Pitt-Johnstown, Pitt-Bradford, Pitt-Titusville], Mar. 3-4, 1972, Pitt Field House and in which Pitt-Greensburg earned the Regional Campus Crown [Pitt-Greensburg 93, Pitt-Johnstown 87]. Items include: Uniform (Jersey #51; Shorts); the 1972 3rd Annual Regional Campus Tournament MVP Player Trophy; Game Basketball Hoop Net.
    [Given to the UPG Archives by Carlyle Carter via Harry Bowser 12/2/2019]
    [n.b. Stored in Archives Utility Cabinet faz 02/06/2020]
    News Article "UPG Hoops Takes Big Step Forward", Greensburg Tribune-Review, 1/11/2020, p. B1, B3
    - Basketball (Men's), 1969-1973, 2020 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 5, Cabinet 1)
  - Basketball (Women's), 4.
    - Basketball (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Cross Country (Men's, Women's), 5.
    - Cross Country (Men's, Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Golf (Men's & Women's), 6.
    - Golf (Men's & Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Lacrosse (Women's), 7.
    - Lacrosse (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Soccer (Men's), 8.
    - Soccer (Men's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Soccer (Women's), 9.
    - Soccer (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Softball (Women's), 10.
    - Softball (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Tennis (Men's), 11.
    - Tennis (Men's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Tennis (Women's), 12.
    - Tennis (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Volleyball (Women's), 13.
    - Volleyball (Women's) (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)
  - Ice Hockey Team, 14.
    See: UPG.RG.38 Ser.: Student Organizations. Ice Hockey Club [Pitt-Greensburg Ice Hockey Team...]
    - Ice Hockey Team (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 3, Box 6)